(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're going back to the movies.
- That's right, we've
got a great lesson today.
And I'm really excited about this dialogue.
I think it's fantastic.
- We have an original English
pod production of a movie trailer.
- So what is a movie trailer?
- Well, whenever you go to the cinema,
before the movie starts, you
have previews of upcoming movies.
- So like, almost an
advertisement for a future movie.
- Exactly.
- Okay.
- So that's a movie trailer, and
that's what we're bringing you today.
- A lot of great language.
You'll commonly hear in action movies.
- Right, so let's start
with vocabulary preview.
- Very vocabulary preview.
- We have one word today, possess.
- Possess. - Possess.
- Possess.
- So when you possess
something, you have it.
- Uh-huh.
- It's in your possession.
- Simple.
- You have it, right?
So in this dialogue, our actors
possess something very important.
- Mm-hmm.
- So let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time,
and it's going to be a little bit fast
and a little bit difficult to understand.
- But don't worry, we'll come back
and explain all of the key language later.
(upbeat music)
- Look.
- In a digital world, even the strongest must fight for survival.
Two people possess a secret,
so valuable, so powerful.
They have to defend it at all costs.
- I don't care where they are.
I don't care what it takes.
You find them and bring them to me!
- They only had one chance,
and their chance was to fight back.
(dramatic music)
- You have to play well!
- Show them up to my new friend!
(dramatic music)
- With a little help from the governor.
- Listen to me, we have
to get to all of them.
Go back and watch!
- The big group will prevent
them from doing their job.
- Double reaction.
- Get down!
- Triple excitement.
- Get them again!
- This summer, nothing
will stand in their way.
- I wanna make 'em all
for the kind of people.
(dramatic music)
- Most one podcast.
English pod, coming to a theater near you.
(dramatic music)
- Wow, so it sounds
like a really good movie.
- I know, when's it coming out?
- I think in 2015.
- Okay, I'll put that in my calendar.
- Okay, let's take a look at the vocabulary
we saw in this dialogue
in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- In language takeaway
today, we have three words.
What's our first one?
- Survival.
- Well, survival is continuing
to live even in really hard times.
- It comes from the verb to survive, right?
So survival is the noun form.
- Right, so maybe you
are lost in the jungle.
- The jungle and you
have to fight for survival.
- Right, you have to try to survive.
- Uh-huh, okay, our next word, defend.
- Defend.
- So let's listen to some examples of
defend so you can understand the meaning.
- Example one.
- We have to defend the castle.
The army is trying to kill the king.
- Example two.
- The soldiers defended
the base in a difficult battle.
- Example three.
- These new machine guns will defend us.
- So basically it's to protect, right?
- Right, to protect from
something that is really harmful.
- Okay, so you would defend your children.
- Uh-huh.
- You would defend your house?
- Your house.
- For your castle?
- Your dog, your cat?
- Yep.
- Okay.
And our last word on
language take away, rough.
- Rough.
- R-O-U-G-H, rough.
- Right, it's got that, uh, yep, sound.
- Uh-huh.
- So it basically means, so when something
it's rough, it's a little bit violent.
- And hard.
- Hard, yep.
- For example, boxing is a rough sport.
- Or hockey is also a rough sport.
- Exactly, so you have rough sports,
or maybe even a person
can be a little bit rough.
- Yes, or that person can play rough.
- Play rough, exactly.
So, rough.
Okay, so we're ready to
listen to our dialogue again.
- And this time it'll
be a little bit slower,
so you can understand the
language a little bit more clearly.
(upbeat music)
- In a digital world, even the
strongest must fight for survival.
Two people possess a secret,
so valuable, so powerful.
They have to defend it at all costs.
- I don't care where they are.
- I don't care what it takes.
You find them and bring them to me.
- They only had one chance
and their chance was to fight back.
- Okay, you want to play rough?
Say hello to my little friend!
With a little help from the governor.
- Listen to me, we have
to get some off of there.
No matter what!
- Nothing will prevent
them from doing their job.
Double the action.
Get down!
Triple the excitement.
- Get down again!
- This summer, nothing
will stand in their way.
- I'm gonna make him an offer.
He can't refuse to hosts one podcast.
- English pod.
Coming to a theater near you.
- So we saw some interesting
phrases in this dialogue.
Let's take a look at
them in Fluency Builder.
- Fluency Builder.
- The first phrase
that we saw at all costs.
- At all costs.
- So let's listen to some examples
before we explain at all costs.
- Example one.
- I'll protect my kids at all costs.
- Example two.
- We have to get this
project done at all costs.
- Example three.
- You find those criminals at all costs.
Well, if you're going to
protect your kids at all costs,
you're going to protect
them, even if it's really hard.
Right, it doesn't matter how
hard it is or what you have to do.
Exactly. You'll do it. At all costs.
Now, let's take a look at our
second phrase for fluency builder,
and it's very similar to at all costs.
Yeah, really similar.
No matter what. No matter what.
No matter what. No matter
what. For example, I'm
going to go on vacation
no matter what my boss says.
Nothing's going to stop you. Right, if
he says no, I'm still going on a vacation.
And I'm going to protect
my kids no matter what.
Exactly. No matter what.
I don't have kids though.
But you will protect them no matter what.
If I had them.
Okay. And our last phrase.
Stand in their way. Stand in their way.
So let's listen to some
examples of stand in someone's
way, and then we'll
come back and explain it.
Example one.
Don't let anything stand
in the way of your goals.
Example two.
I'm going to find that guy and
nothing is going to stand in my way.
Example three.
I don't care what
happens. I'm going to get
that money, and you
better not stand in my way.
So when something
stands in your way, it's
it's preventing you
from reaching your goal.
From reaching your goal,
right? But we can also
have somebody standing
in your way physically.
Like really you're standing close to
me and I can't pass through the door.
Right. So maybe the person is at the door
and it's standing in my way. I can't go in.
Yeah. Okay. But here
we're not really talking
about a real thing,
right? That you can touch.
Right. It's more of some
obstacle that's preventing
you from reaching your goals or
from doing what you want to do.
Yep. So now we can listen to our dialogue
again, and now you can understand these
words that we've just
talked about in a digital
world, even the strongest
must fight for survival.
Two people possess a secret
so valuable, so powerful.
They have to
defend it at all costs.
I don't care whether I don't care what it
takes. You find them and bring them to me.
They only had one chance, and
their chance was to fight back.
With a little help from
the governor, there's
a chance we have
to get to all of them.
Go back, go back.
Nothing will prevent them
from doing their job.
Double reaction. Get down.
Triple excitement. Get down again. This
somewhere, nothing will stand in their way.
I want to make them all
forget them with people.
Two hosts. One podcast. English pod.
Coming to a theater near you.
I know that you're a
big movie fan, right?
Yeah, I'm a big movie
fan. I usually watch maybe
three or five movies a
week. Really? Yeah. Wow.
Many students of English
like to watch movies
as a way to improve
their English. That's one of
the best ways to learn English
is through songs and movies.
What do you think are some useful movies
that people can watch to practice English?
Well, I would recommend children's movies.
Really? Yeah, they have simple vocabulary,
but they have very common
language. And also what's
happening in the movie is very
easy to understand and to follow.
So you can see the action
and then hear the word.
Exactly. So if you like to watch movies,
rent a DVD or go buy a DVD, watch it in
the original language
with English subtitles.
So you should watch it in
English with English subtitles.
Yeah. And what are subtitles?
Subtitles are the words that you see at
the bottom of the screen that translate.
Okay. What the
people are saying. Okay.
Yeah, that's the best thing
to do. Try that exercise.
If you have a pen and paper with you, it's
much better. You can pause the movie right
down the word you
don't understand and then
maybe review it later.
That's a really good tip.
I always tell my students
that they should watch
movies, listen to music,
read the newspaper,
and write down at least five
new words or phrases a week.
Yeah. Yeah. It's a really good
exercise and you'll improve a lot. Yes.
So everyone, we want you to go
out and watch a movie in English.
Turn on the subtitles and write
down some new vocabulary.
Exactly. And if you have any comments
or questions or maybe even suggestions,
you can come to our
website at englishpod.
com and leave them
in our community page.
Now Marco and I are
always around to help you
and we love to hear
about what you're learning
and what movies you're watching.
Exactly. So we're out of time today.
We'll see you guys next time.
Until then, it's goodbye.
(upbeat music)